<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Wrangling with R</title>
    <link>https://xiaoruizhu.github.io/data-wrangling/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Data Wrangling with R</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 23:08:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://xiaoruizhu.github.io/data-wrangling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Schedule</title>
      <link>https://xiaoruizhu.github.io/data-wrangling/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 23:22:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xiaoruizhu.github.io/data-wrangling/schedule/</guid>
      <description>   Session Description     1 Introduction     Intro to data wrangling, R, and course outline    Base R   2 Reproducible Documents and Importing Data     Managing your workflow and reproducibility    Importing data and understanding the basics of it   3 Tidy Data and Data Manipulation     Tidying &amp;amp; preparing data for analysis    Data manipulation   4 Relational Data and More Tidyverse Packages     Relational data    Leveraging the Tidyverse to simplify data wrangling   5 Data Visualizations     Data visualization   6 Creating Efficient Code in R     Control statements &amp;amp; iteration    Writing functions   7 Introduction to Applied Modeling     Correlation &amp;amp; regression    Introduction to machine learning    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Project</title>
      <link>https://xiaoruizhu.github.io/data-wrangling/final_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xiaoruizhu.github.io/data-wrangling/final_project/</guid>
      <description>Purpose The purpose of this individual/pair final project is to put to work the tools and knowledge that you gain throughout this course. This provides you with multiple benefits.
 It will provide you with more experience using data wrangling tools on real life data sets. It helps you become a self-directed learner. As a data scientist, a large part of your job is to self-direct your learning and interests to find unique and creative ways to find insights in data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Engagement Guidelines</title>
      <link>https://xiaoruizhu.github.io/data-wrangling/engagement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xiaoruizhu.github.io/data-wrangling/engagement/</guid>
      <description>10% of your grade will be determined by your level of engagement. Engagement will include participating in class discussions, small group projects, providing quality peer review of code, and being involved in discussions on Canvas. At the end of the term I will have all students perform a peer assessment of their small group members. This assessment will rate each member in several areas regarding:
 Reviewing and providing constructive feedback regarding your code Engaging in quality discussions with the group to improve code knowledge Working well as a team member in the small group activities etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mid-term Expectations</title>
      <link>https://xiaoruizhu.github.io/data-wrangling/mid-term/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xiaoruizhu.github.io/data-wrangling/mid-term/</guid>
      <description>You may work with one other person on the midterm and final projects if you wish. Once you decide on working solo or as a pair, your decision remains for the rest of the course (i.e., you can&amp;rsquo;t decide to work alone or join someone after submitting the midterm. Please read the final project page before reading any further.
Throughout the term you will progressively create your final project. Your mid-term project is to submit the work you have completed midway through the course for a progress evaluation, where you have fully completed standards 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1 (October 18)</title>
      <link>https://xiaoruizhu.github.io/data-wrangling/week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xiaoruizhu.github.io/data-wrangling/week-1/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to week 1! Although we will not meet in class until the end of this week (Monday, October 18th), I do not want to waste time in getting started. We only have 7 weeks together (😢) so I want to pack each week as full as possible. I am assuming you have fully read the syllabus by now but if not please do so that you understand how this class is structured and what is expected of you.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
